<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-07T14:28:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><subtitle>This website has a selection of published projects spanning art projects, collective productions and work in education.</subtitle><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><entry><title type="html">Rare Earth Walks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Rare-Earth-Walks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rare Earth Walks" /><published>2023-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Rare-Earth-Walks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Rare-Earth-Walks/">&lt;p&gt; Rare Earth Walks is a field research activity to examine the relations between earth and technology and consider computational hardware as geological artifacts
&lt;br /&gt;
As part of this group expedition everyone is invited to go &lt;i&gt;fossicking&lt;/i&gt; for precious stones, metals and minerals. Various assistive tools are used to survey the terrain and learn about the different ways of prospecting the land throughout history from ancient stone collection, water divination and metal detecting.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The collective finds are then used to create an 'elementary computer' - an assembled schematic of various found materials that can then be used to learn about the trace elements of various metals integral in electronics and hardware required for renewable energy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;*Fossicking is a term used in Australia, New Zealand and Cornwall to describe recreational prospecting.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Images by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ibifeherphotography.com/&quot;&gt;Ibi Feher Photography&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rare Earth Walks was a site specific commission for&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.control-shift.network/artwork.html?artwork=rare-earth-walks&quot;&gt; Control Shift Festival 2023.&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Rare Earth Walks is a field research activity to examine the relations between earth and technology and consider computational hardware as geological artifacts As part of this group expedition everyone is invited to go fossicking for precious stones, metals and minerals. Various assistive tools are used to survey the terrain and learn about the different ways of prospecting the land throughout history from ancient stone collection, water divination and metal detecting. The collective finds are then used to create an 'elementary computer' - an assembled schematic of various found materials that can then be used to learn about the trace elements of various metals integral in electronics and hardware required for renewable energy. *Fossicking is a term used in Australia, New Zealand and Cornwall to describe recreational prospecting. Images by Ibi Feher Photography Rare Earth Walks was a site specific commission for Control Shift Festival 2023.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Medialab Matedero</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/medialab-matedero/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Medialab Matedero" /><published>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/medialab-matedero</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/medialab-matedero/">&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt; Considering electronic devices as geological artifacts, what stories and tales can be unearthed through embodied practices?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was project lead for a collaborative residency as part of ‘The Metabolic Sublime’ at Medialab Matedero for 2 weeks in February 2023.  
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We workshopped process based methods for excavating minerals (such as dowsing, detecting and foraging) and designed lo-fi instruments with found materials to create embodied circuits of energy transfer and mythical enactment.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By evoking mythical tales associated with stones and minerals we developed a number of participatory methodologies for re-configuring humans relation to stones &amp;amp; technology and fostered new paradigms towards ‘clean’ energy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Residency Mentors: Marina Otero,Joana Moll &amp;amp; Liam Young &lt;br /&gt;
Residency collaborators: Bruno Szenk, Irene de Boer, Cecilia Serrano Moreno, Lila Izquierdo &amp;amp; Lena Buzueva.&lt;br /&gt;
Guest Workshop by: Maria Lucia Peña Ardila. &lt;br /&gt; 
Video documentation was created by Lila Izquierdo and is can be viewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=31oE_4-bZVk&quot;&gt; here. &lt;/a&gt;




&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Considering electronic devices as geological artifacts, what stories and tales can be unearthed through embodied practices? I was project lead for a collaborative residency as part of ‘The Metabolic Sublime’ at Medialab Matedero for 2 weeks in February 2023. We workshopped process based methods for excavating minerals (such as dowsing, detecting and foraging) and designed lo-fi instruments with found materials to create embodied circuits of energy transfer and mythical enactment. By evoking mythical tales associated with stones and minerals we developed a number of participatory methodologies for re-configuring humans relation to stones &amp;amp; technology and fostered new paradigms towards ‘clean’ energy. Residency Mentors: Marina Otero,Joana Moll &amp;amp; Liam Young Residency collaborators: Bruno Szenk, Irene de Boer, Cecilia Serrano Moreno, Lila Izquierdo &amp;amp; Lena Buzueva. Guest Workshop by: Maria Lucia Peña Ardila. Video documentation was created by Lila Izquierdo and is can be viewed here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interspeciestreaty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/interspeciestreaty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interspeciestreaty" /><published>2022-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/interspeciestreaty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/interspeciestreaty/">&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Treaty of Finsbury Park 2025&lt;/i&gt; is a collaborative project that depicts the story of the dawning of interspecies democracy. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Based around a set of LARPs – or live action role play games – the Treaty of Finsbury Park 2025 is played from more-than-human perspectives to encourage the blooming of a bountiful biodiversity and interspecies political action.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
 I joined this large scale project as a collaborative artist and LARP host, hosting the online assemblies as my mentor species, Scirius (a North London Squirrel) and worked on the festival production for the live events in Finsbury Park.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

The project was originally developed in a collaboration between Furtherfield and The New Design Congress. The first 3 years were supported by CreaTures Creative Practices for Transformational Futures. You can read more about the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.furtherfield.org/the-treaty-of-finsbury-park-2025/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
and sign up for 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/furtherfield/6dqud0ocsh&quot;&gt;updates &lt;/a&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="production" /><summary type="html">The Treaty of Finsbury Park 2025 is a collaborative project that depicts the story of the dawning of interspecies democracy. Based around a set of LARPs – or live action role play games – the Treaty of Finsbury Park 2025 is played from more-than-human perspectives to encourage the blooming of a bountiful biodiversity and interspecies political action. I joined this large scale project as a collaborative artist and LARP host, hosting the online assemblies as my mentor species, Scirius (a North London Squirrel) and worked on the festival production for the live events in Finsbury Park.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/17/test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2022-06-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-06-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/17/test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/17/test.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello world&lt;/strong&gt;, this is my first Jekyll blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you like it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><summary type="html">Welcome</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weekly Fluxus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/weekly-fluxus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekly Fluxus" /><published>2020-09-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/weekly-fluxus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/weekly-fluxus/">&lt;p&gt;A web app that sends a list of subscribers a random fluxus performance work once a week. The service selects an event score each week from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thing.net/~grist/ld/fluxusworkbook.pdf&quot;&gt;The Fluxus Performance Workbook&lt;/a&gt; (Performance Research e-publication, 2002) and features over 30 different artists and hundreds of event scores for peformative happenings. I hope that by sending them out via a mobile text service will mean these event scores can become occasional interruptions into our daily routines and offer performative actions and imagined events during periods of social isolation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">A web app that sends a list of subscribers a random fluxus performance work once a week. The service selects an event score each week from the The Fluxus Performance Workbook (Performance Research e-publication, 2002) and features over 30 different artists and hundreds of event scores for peformative happenings. I hope that by sending them out via a mobile text service will mean these event scores can become occasional interruptions into our daily routines and offer performative actions and imagined events during periods of social isolation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">True Insights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/true-insights/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="True Insights" /><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/true-insights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/true-insights/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;True Insights&lt;/i&gt; is the name of a fictional focus group created as part of a series of live action role play events that critically examine the effects of decentralized technology. The focus group explored consumer ethics and attitudes towards data transparency in the style of a market research focus group. Each participant was allocated fictional personas and given pseudonyms with which they could enact a critical response to the increased use of data transparency and surveillance in society. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The True Insights Company was concieved by Ruth Catlow of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.furtherfield.org/&quot;&gt;Futherfield&lt;/a&gt; and Designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://r-b.site/&quot;&gt; Robbie Blundell&lt;/a&gt;.The findings of the research is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://glass-houses.cs.ucl.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="production" /><summary type="html">True Insights is the name of a fictional focus group created as part of a series of live action role play events that critically examine the effects of decentralized technology. The focus group explored consumer ethics and attitudes towards data transparency in the style of a market research focus group. Each participant was allocated fictional personas and given pseudonyms with which they could enact a critical response to the increased use of data transparency and surveillance in society. The True Insights Company was concieved by Ruth Catlow of Futherfield and Designed by Robbie Blundell.The findings of the research is available here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Take The Words</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/take-the-words/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Take The Words" /><published>2019-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/take-the-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/take-the-words/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Take The Words Right Out Of My Mouth&lt;/i&gt; is a performance that invites the audience to have a dialogue with themselves using an artificial clone of their voice. Using machine learning to replicate the human voice we aim to sonify the internal monologue of the individual and experiment with conversation mediums to amplify internal voices.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The performance was commissioned by Setup and made in collaboration with Nina Goedegebure. All images by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sebastiaanterburg.nl/&quot;&gt; Sebastiaan ter Burg&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Take The Words Right Out Of My Mouth is a performance that invites the audience to have a dialogue with themselves using an artificial clone of their voice. Using machine learning to replicate the human voice we aim to sonify the internal monologue of the individual and experiment with conversation mediums to amplify internal voices. The performance was commissioned by Setup and made in collaboration with Nina Goedegebure. All images by Sebastiaan ter Burg.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Human Ml</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/human-ml/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Ml" /><published>2019-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/human-ml</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/human-ml/">&lt;p&gt;
In this 3 day workshop MA students explored the use of Machine Learning and produced some proof of concepts based on experimental data methods. The course examined machine learning through the history of 20th century experimental art practices such as Fluxus, Oulipo and the Situationists. Students were introduced to conceptual and technical approaches to working with machine learning in (un)creative and adverserial ways and produced some machine learning protypes using Python and TensorFlow.
 &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="teaching" /><summary type="html">In this 3 day workshop MA students explored the use of Machine Learning and produced some proof of concepts based on experimental data methods. The course examined machine learning through the history of 20th century experimental art practices such as Fluxus, Oulipo and the Situationists. Students were introduced to conceptual and technical approaches to working with machine learning in (un)creative and adverserial ways and produced some machine learning protypes using Python and TensorFlow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cologne Maiden Name Workshop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cologne-maiden-name-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cologne Maiden Name Workshop" /><published>2019-08-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cologne-maiden-name-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cologne-maiden-name-workshop/">&lt;p&gt;
In this workshop participants explored methods to produce locative based experiences as part of Noordkaap’s post-futuristic taxi rides. Participants were introduced to site specific media art and explored methods used by the Situationists and the mathematical literature group Oulipo to produce their own artworks and happenings that took place as part of the taxi ride &lt;a href=&quot;/Cologne-Maiden-Name/&quot;&gt;Cologne, What is Your Mother's Maiden Name?&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="teaching" /><summary type="html">In this workshop participants explored methods to produce locative based experiences as part of Noordkaap’s post-futuristic taxi rides. Participants were introduced to site specific media art and explored methods used by the Situationists and the mathematical literature group Oulipo to produce their own artworks and happenings that took place as part of the taxi ride Cologne, What is Your Mother's Maiden Name?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cologne Maiden Name</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Cologne-Maiden-Name/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cologne Maiden Name" /><published>2019-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Cologne-Maiden-Name</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Cologne-Maiden-Name/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cologne, What is your Mother’s maiden Name?&lt;/i&gt;  was a participatory psychometric taxi tour of the city of Cologne that used GPS, psychometrics and augmented reality to create psychological portraits of the city. The taxi ride was commissioned as part of a series of post-futuristic tours of the city by the nomadic arts organisation &lt;i&gt;Noordkaap&lt;/i&gt; in partnership with the &lt;i&gt;Akademie der Künste der Welt&lt;/i&gt; . Members of the public were asked play ‘ispy’ and record their experience during their taxi ride as they explored different parts of the city. These written observations were then analysed for their psychometric properties, similar to the techniques used by companies such as Cambridge Analytica to target consumers in online advertising and political campaigning to produce a psycho-geography of the city.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The psychometric taxi tour was produced as part of a series of &lt;a href=&quot;/cologne-maiden-name-workshop/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with artists from the Akademie youth program Emma Bieck, Johannes Hoffmann, Bessie Normand, Argia Helen Wehner. A publication documenting the different taxi rides was produced in June 2020 and is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuu.com/maxdovey/docs/nk-taxi-inside_black_web&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Dovey</name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Cologne, What is your Mother’s maiden Name? was a participatory psychometric taxi tour of the city of Cologne that used GPS, psychometrics and augmented reality to create psychological portraits of the city. The taxi ride was commissioned as part of a series of post-futuristic tours of the city by the nomadic arts organisation Noordkaap in partnership with the Akademie der Künste der Welt . Members of the public were asked play ‘ispy’ and record their experience during their taxi ride as they explored different parts of the city. These written observations were then analysed for their psychometric properties, similar to the techniques used by companies such as Cambridge Analytica to target consumers in online advertising and political campaigning to produce a psycho-geography of the city. The psychometric taxi tour was produced as part of a series of workshops in collaboration with artists from the Akademie youth program Emma Bieck, Johannes Hoffmann, Bessie Normand, Argia Helen Wehner. A publication documenting the different taxi rides was produced in June 2020 and is available here.</summary></entry></feed>